

EDUCATION

Virginia Tech

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Visual Communication Design

Bachelor of Arts, French Minor, Art History

SKILLS & PROGRAMS

SASS

CSS

HTMI

Visual Studio Code (VSC)

Sublime Text

Adobe Creative Suite

Microsoft Office Suite

Google Suite

Slack

Workfront

Confluence

Marketo

Acquia

JSON

Javascript/jQuery (some)
ColdFusion (some)

DESIGN AWARDS

2010 American Design Award Winner, Web Design

2010 Student Silver District Addy®, Photography

2010 Student Silver District Addy®, Packaging Design

2010 Student Silver Regional Addy®, Packaging Design

2010 Logo Publish, Logo Lounge® 6

ABOUT

With more than 10 years of corporate experience, Lara Latham is a creative web and graphic designer, front end developer, and visual problem solver. Known for learning quickly, working efficiently with strong attention to detail, and working independently with minimal supervision, as well as collaborating in a team environment. Referred to as the "go-to" person when it comes to process and insight of best practices.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Web Designer

EAB. Adult Learner Recruitment

11/2021 – Present Richmond, VA / Remote

- Design and code a seamless branded user experience from clients' websites to EAB's marketed landing pages, websites, graphic emails, and web applications, built in proprietary frameworks.
- Create and gather digital assets, while troubleshooting website issues in collaboration with project management and web development teams.
- Successfully manage the largest book of clients, and the most complex on the web design team.
- Collaborate with copywriters, art directors, and digital marketers to strategically achieve the correct solution for each client through print, web, ads, and paid search.
- Produced creative work that yielded 100% client satisfaction based on client survey results.
- Be an expert and advanced user of existing online and web management platforms, content management, FTP management, illustration management and prototyping tools.
- Interview candidates, train, and mentor new hires for the web design team.
- Smoothly transitioned all client work into a new marketing automation platform twice, learning each platforms' new set of processes and necessary code.
- Work in a fast-pace environment with extremely fast turnaround times and deadlines.
- Update existing or design and code new landing pages for existing clients every 6 months based on new best practices based on market findings and testing results.
- Work alongside a team of proofreaders and quality control experts to ensure each product is accurate and functionally correct.

Senior Web Designer

EAB, Adult Learner Recruitment

10/2018 — 11/2021 Richmond, VA / Remote

Web Designer (ALR)

EAB. Adult Learner Recruitment

06/2017 - 10/2018 Richmond, VA

- Helped to pioneer a new start-up division to market to the adult learner population through several market tests, new products, and new platforms.
- Helped to hire and mentor new web designers, as well as train other creative roles as programs and processes constantly evolved and changed.
- Quickly learned and worked in new platforms as the best marketing solutions were uncovered. Each new platform required new code knowledge and process.



Web, Graphic, & Print Designer · Front End Developer · Marketer mrslaralatham@gmail.com · 804.347.8081 · Charlotte, NC 28278 linkedin.com/in/laralatham · name pronounced: [L-air-uh L-ay-thumb]

INTERESTS

Wake surfing Interior Design Home DIYs Craft DIYs Painting

Web Designer (Undergrad)

10/2015 - 06/2017Richmond, VA

EAB, Undergraduate Enrollment Services

• Learned HTML, CSS, and SASS in less than three months.

• Worked exclusively in SASS to create landing pages, web applications, and websites.

Senior Art Director

09/2013 - 10/2015

EAB, Undergraduate Enrollment Services

Richmond, VA

- · Managed the largest book of clients in the art director team.
- Worked with clients' branding to create direct mail, and collect all art for FTP.
- · Mentored and trained new art directors.
- Worked alongside copywriters and web designers to create a cohesive experience.

Art Director

11/2011 - 09/2013

EAB, Undergraduate Enrollment Services

Richmond, VA

Associate Art Director

02/2011 - 11/2011

EAB. Undergraduate Enrollment Services

Richmond, VA

Freelance Visual & Graphic Designer

05/2008 - present Richmond, VA

Lara Latham

- Created visual design boards for corporate interior spaces, sourced all necessary items for the spaces, and executed the design plan for a full interior redesign.
- Worked with Richmond, Virginia-based companies like Tang & Biscuit and Leonardo's Pizza to redesign all of their various menus (in restaurant, takeout, tabletop, etc).
- Created new brand and identity system for a start-up in Richmond, VA including logos, business cards, one sheets, brochures, and website content creation and design implementation.

Graphic Designer

05/2007 - 06/2010

Yogg

Richmond, VA

· Personally mentored by the owner, while working with many Richmond-area clients on print pieces with a focus on branding and identity.